## <u>LinkedIn</u> +55 11 95300 1450



henrique.phgb@gmail.com



Santo André, SP - Brasil

Passionate about technology, computers and programming. One of my skills is my quick habituation with any work environment and language, because for me to program is to create, accept challenges and solve them.

I have been working for about 7 years with systems development, involving web applications, desktop and also games. Recently I decided to graduate in the area to get more experiences and skills.

I have facilities to learn new technologies, and I also always keep up to date on the entire professional context around me.

#### Education

## Computer Engineering, Faculdade Meta, Macapá – AP / Brazil

February 2015 - November 2020

#### Skills

## **Programming Languages**

Java	C++	Ruby	Javascript	
3 years	1 year	5 years	3 years	

#### **Frameworks**

Ruby on Rails	Flutter	Angular	QT
5 years	1 year	2 years	1 year

#### **Databases**

MySQL	PostgreSQL	SQLite	MongoDB
3 vears	2 vears	1 vear	2 vears

## FullStack Developer at Nuuvem, Rio de Janeiro - RJ / Brazil

January 2022 - Present

Create and implement modern, resilient and easy-to-use web interfaces and help maintain and develop the current platform. I work in the backoffice squad taking care of bug fixing and implementing new features as per the sprint scope. We work a lot with code review and scrum principles.

Stack: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Angular.

# **Employment History**

## FullStack Developer at OrçaFascio, Santo André – SP / Brazil

September 2019 – December 2021

Acting as a web developer, I worked individually in the creation of the planning module, in which he is responsible for the temporal dimensioning of a work through the definition of dates in the activities. It has tools such as schedule, balance line and network. As well as in system maintenance.

Stack: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JS.

## Freelancer Programmer – Food ordering and delivery system

**August 2019 – October 2019** 

I worked as a team in the development of a food delivery system, similar to ifood, with the system for order management and control, and the mobile application to carry out orders. I worked mainly in Backend and partially in Frontend and Mobile.

Stack: Ruby on Rails, Flutter, MySQL, Angular.

## Freelancer Programmer – Medical appointment scheduling system

February 2019 - June 2019

I worked individually in the development of a system of scheduling medical consultations, where users registered through the application, and then could schedule appointments with medical specialists, in addition to managing their own electronic medical records. The system was developed for user management on the platform and applications for doctors and patients. I worked at Backend, Frontend and Mobile.

Stack: SpringBoot, PostgreSQL, Flutter, Angular.

# Trainee in Federal Institute of Education, Science and Technology of the Amapá – IFAP, Macapá - AP

July 2014 - November 2014

I worked both in the physical and logical part involving configuration of servers, and the network of the institute. Later I started acting as a programmer, developing a mini client access to the user management system for consultation, registration and deletion of users through API.

T	o	0	S

RSpec	Capybara	Cucumbe	r JUnit	Mocha
Postman	Insomnia	Sidekiq	OpenGL	DirectX
ElasticSearch	Line	ux G	ithub Actions	GitLab CI
Microservices	Concepts	Cloud	API REST	CI/CD
Agile methodolo	gies S	crum	Git Aut	omated testing

## Academic Activities

Knowledge

### Maven-X1-MK2

Development of a hexagon robot. The project covered both the physical assembly of the robot, as well as the arrangement and configuration of the hardware and the control and movement software of the robot. Combining in hardware a Raspberry Pi zero, accompanied by a PCA9685 module for control of the servo motors of the robot legs, and the software all developed in Java.

#### **SODEV**

Development of a prototype for detecting objects for visually impaired people from the height of a person's thigh down. The prototype had the knee brace containing the detector, and a clock for audible warning of possible objects in front. The control system was developed in C++.

## **MetaFighter**

Development of an Android video game with the same idea as the famous classic Mortal Kombat, using the same techniques of development and filming, using as characters the teachers of the institution.

Languages	Inglês	Português	
	Advanced	Fluent	